[Why don't we eat bugs?]
For centuries, people have consumed bugs,
everything from beetles /ˈbiːtəl 甲壳虫/
to caterpillars /ˈkætəˌpɪlə 毛虫 履带/, locusts /ˈləʊkəst 蝗虫；洋槐/,
grasshoppers /ˈɡrɑːsˌhɒpə 蚱蜢/, termites /ˈtɜːmaɪt 白蚁/, and dragonflies.
The practice even has a name:
entomophagy /ˌentəˈmɒfædʒɪ 食虫习惯/.
Early hunter-gatherers /ˈɡæðərə/
probably learned from animals
that foraged /ˈfɒrɪdʒ 饲料 觅食/ for protein/ˈprəʊtiːn/-rich insects /ˈɪnsɛkt/
and followed suit /suːt 相配/.
As we evolved /ɪˈvɒlv 进化/ and bugs
became part of our dietary /ˈdaɪətərɪ 饮食的/ tradition,
they fulfilled the role
of both staple /ˈsteɪpəl 主食/ food and delicacy /ˈdɛlɪkəsɪ 佳肴；珍馐/.
In ancient Greece, cicadas /sɪˈkɑːdə 蝉/
were considered luxury snacks.
And even the Romans found
beetle /ˈbiːtəl 甲壳虫 / larvae /ˈlɑːviː  larvaS/ to be scrumptious /ˈskrʌmpʃəs 非常美味的/.
Why have we lost our taste for bugs?
The reason for our rejection
is historical,
and the story probably begins
around 10,000 BC in the Fertile /ˈfɜːtaɪl/ Crescent /ˈkrɛsənt 新月/,
a place in the Middle East
that was a major birthplace
of agriculture.
Back then, our once-nomadic /nəʊˈmædɪk 游牧的/ ancestors /ˈænsɛstə/
began to settle in the Crescent.
And as they learned to farm crops /krɒp/
and domesticate /dəˈmestɪkeɪt 驯养/ animals there,
attitudes changed,
rippling /ˈrɪpəl  涟漪/ outwards towards Europe
and the rest of the Western world.
As farming took off,
people might have spurned /spɜːn 一脚踢开/
bugs as mere /mɪə 只不过的/ pests
that destroyed their crops.
Populations grew,
and the West became urbanized /城市化的/,
weakening connections
with our foraging /ˈfɒrɪdʒ 饲料 觅食/ past.
People simply forgot
their bug-rich history.
Today, for people not
accustomed to entomophagy /ˌentəˈmɒfædʒɪ 食虫习惯/,
bugs are just an irritant /ˈɪrɪtənt 恼人的/.
They sting /stɪŋ 毒刺/ and bite and infest /ɪnˈfest 侵扰；寄生于/ our food.
We feel an "sick /恶心/ factor"
associated with them
and are disgusted /dɪsˈɡʌstɪd/
by the prospect /prɔspekt 期望/ of cooking insects.
Almost 2,000 insect species
are turned into food,
forming a big part of everyday diets
for two billion people around the world.
Countries in the tropics /ˈtrɒpɪks/
are the keenest /kiːn 热心的/ consumers,
because culturally, it's acceptable.
Species in those regions
are also large, diverse /daɪˈvɜ:s/,
and tend to congregate /ˈkɒŋɡrɪɡɪt （使）聚集/ in groups or swarms /swɔːm 一大群 成群地移动/
that make them easy to harvest.
Take Cambodia /kæmˈbəʊdɪə/ in Southeast Asia
where huge tarantulas /təˈræntʃʊlə 狼蛛/ are gathered,
fried, and sold in the marketplace.
In southern Africa,
the juicy /ˈdʒuːsɪ 多汁的/ mopane /mɒˈpɑːnɪ/ worm is a dietary /ˈdaɪətərɪ 饮食的/ staple /ˈsteɪpəl 主食/,
simmered /ˈsɪmə 炖/ in a spicy /ˈspaɪsɪ/ sauce /sɔːs/
or eaten dried and salted.
And in Mexico/ˈmɛksɪˌkəʊ/, chopped jumiles
are toasted with garlic /ˈɡɑːlɪk 大蒜/, lemon /ˈlɛmən/, and salt.
Bugs can be eaten whole to make up a meal
or ground into flour /ˈflaʊə 面粉/, powder,
and paste /peɪst 面团/ to add to food.
But it's not all about taste.
They're also healthy.
In fact, scientists say entomophagy /ˌentəˈmɒfædʒɪ/
could be a cost-effective solution
for developing countries
that are food insecure.
Insects can contain up to 80% protein,
the body's vital /ˈvaɪtəl/ building blocks,
and are also high in energy-rich fat,
fiber /ˈfaɪbə/, and micronutrients /ˌmaɪkrəʊˈnjuːtrɪənt 微量营养素/
like vitamins and minerals /mineral/.
Did you know that most edible insects
contain the same amount
or even more mineral iron than beef,
making them a huge, untapped /ʌnˈtæpt 未利用的/ resource
when you consider that iron deficiency /dɪˈfɪʃənsɪ 缺乏/
is currently the most common
nutritional problem in the world?
The mealworm /ˈmiːlˌwɜːm 黄粉虫幼虫/
is another nutritious /njuːˈtrɪʃəs/ example.
The yellow beetle larvae are native
to America and easy to farm.
They have a high vitamin content /ˈkɒntɛnt/,
loads of healthy minerals /mineral/,
and can contain up to 50% protein,
almost as much as in an equivalent
amount of beef.
To cook, simply sauté /ˈsəʊteɪ 爆炒的/ in butter and salt
or roast and drizzle /ˈdrɪzəl 毛毛雨/ with chocolate
for a crunchy /ˈkrʌntʃɪ 脆的/ snack /snæk/.
What you have to overcome in "sick factor,"
you gain in nutrition and taste.
Indeed, bugs can be delicious.
Mealworms taste like roasted nuts.
Locusts are similar to shrimp.
Crickets /ˈkrɪkɪt 蟋蟀/, some people say,
have an aroma /əˈrəʊmə 芳香/ of popcorn.
Farming insects for food
also has less environmental impact
than livestock farms do
because insects emit /ɪˈmɪt 排出/
far less greenhouse gas
and use up less space, water, and food.
Socioeconomically, bug production
could uplift people
in developing countries
since insect farms can be small scale,
highly productive, and yet
relatively inexpensive to keep.
Insects can also be turned
into more sustainable food for livestock /ˈlaɪvˌstɒk 家畜/
and can be reared /rɪə/ on organic waste,
like vegetable peelings /piːl 皮 剥；削/,
that might otherwise
just end up rotting /rɒt 腐烂/ in landfills /ˈlændˌfɪl 垃圾填埋场/.
Feeling hungry yet?
Faced with a plate of fried crickets /ˈkrɪkɪt 蟋蟀 /,
most people today would still recoil /rɪˈkɔɪl 畏缩/,
imagining all those legs and feelers /ˈfiːlə 试探；触角/
getting stuck /stʌk 陷入/ between their teeth.
But think of a lobster.
It's pretty much just a giant insect
with legs and feelers /ˈfiːlə 试探；触角/ galore /ɡəˈlɔː 大量地  /
that was once regarded
as an inferior /ɪnˈfɪərɪə 低等的/, repulsive /rɪˈpʌlsɪv 令人厌恶的；排斥的/ food.
Now, lobster is a delicacy /ˈdɛlɪkəsɪ 佳肴；珍馐/.
Can the same paradigm /ˈpærəˌdaɪm 范例/ shift
happen for bugs?
So, give it a try!
Pop that insect into your mouth,
and savor /ˈseɪvə 品尝/ the crunch /krʌntʃ 嘎吱嘎吱地嚼/.